

Satguru Saran Satsangi P.

UI / UX designer | Product Designer | Researcher



satsangi77@gmail.com



psssatsangi.com



Indianapolis, Indiana Open to move



Hello, I'm Saran. I love being creative, exploring and broadening my horizons, doing things in high quality and giving stunning user experience in my products. I'm enthusiast of user experience design and product design. I am also a business oriented person with good knowledge in business model and value map.

Experiences

October 2017 - Present

UI/UX Designer (Volunteer Position) New Wisdom, LLC

I am designing the UI for a E.com. website, and integrating Virtual try-on into the website for users to try sunglasses at home.

January 2017 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant (UI/UX)

Comet Lab SoIC, IUPUI

I worked as UX Designer for developing a web based application for Merit-based Incentive Payment System to determine if clinicians are providing good care for patients in efficient way. This tool significantly reduced the overall administrative burdens for physicians and advisors.

June 2014 - July 2014 (Internship)

UI/UX Designer

The Workshop

Cairo, Egypt

I was the Team Lead and UX Designer for implementing a website for the NGO, which is used for training Egyptian women in different fields.

Education

January 2017 – Present(Expected August 2019)

MS Human Computer Interaction

Indiana University Purdue University Indianapolis GPA: 3.6

August 2011 - May 2016

B.Tech. Information Technology

Gayatri Vidya Parishad college of Engineering

Projects

August 2017 - October 2017

Healthy Connect: Connecting you to health

(GE Appliances design challenge)

Group project (Role: Operations Manager)

We designed IOT product and service based business incorparating Meal Orchestration, Health and Delivery services.

October 2017 - November 2017

"Ava" The next step to InfoLink

(Crown Equipments design challenge)

Group project (Role: Design Manager)

We designed a new application for fleet management, and also designed a Augmented Reality concept for warehouse managers to monitor and check data and performance

October 2017 - Present

Virtual Try-on

(Role: UI/UX Designer)

Integrated virtual try-on into a Ecom website of a brand. Also worked on designing the UI of the VTO.

August 2017 – October 2017

Amazon Prime Kitchen

(Amazon design challenge)

Group project (Role: Product Manager)

We designed a novel automated delivery system to deliver healthy and fresh food in a hassle free and

optimized way.

Tools

Mac OS X Sketch Balsamia Adobe Creative Suite Github

Design Skills

Mobile design Prototyping Web designing UI design UX design Illustration Photography Animation



HTML CSS Javascript MySQL Java threeis

References

Robert Skipworth Comer, M.S.

Research Associate, Media Arts and Science

Sonny E. Kirkley

Director of Product/UX Design New Wisdom, LLC